JUJUTSU KAISEN
Shibuya Incident
Do you remember
the ways to rid cursed
spirits from our world?
Regardless of which method is pursued,
it means advancing humanity
to the next stage.
Now, I need to buy time for Larue to act.
Humanity's next stage is
freeing itself from cursed energy.
No. It's optimizing cursed energy.
Uh, I don't get it, either.
I thought you already gave on your plan
twelve years ago, when Zen'in Toji died.
I was talking to Geto-kun, you know.
Well, whatever.
I went back to my original idea.
Besides, there's a big hole
in your optimization plan.
Extremely few sorcerers and cursed spirits
emerge in other countries compared to Japan.
So Tengen's barriers should be
indispensable to your optimization plan.
Using Tengen to optimize
cursed energy would mean
only the humans of this nation
would become sorcerers.
Japan would practically have
a monopoly on cursed energy.
Other nations, especially that superpower,
wouldn't stand by and allow that.
Flesh-and-blood humans
would become an energy source.
It's easy enough to imagine
what misfortune that would bring.
That's a world far removed
from the ideals I pursue.
So what?
For one thing, our objectives are different.
I don't desire a world
without cursed spirits
or any sort of idyllic peace.
Non-sorcerers, sorcerers, cursed spirits...
Those are all possibilities
for the shape of cursed
energy that is mankind.
Though that shouldn't be
anywhere near the full extent.
I tried to give rise
to other possibilities
for mankind on my own.
But that didn't work out.
Everything that I created myself
was limited by the bounds
of my own potential.
The answer was always
glimmering darkly within chaos.
Do you understand?
What I should have created
was chaos that went
beyond my own control.
I've already finished
extracting the technique.
There was a cursed spirit
called Mahito, right?!
The one with the technique
that let it interfere with souls!
That guy absorbed it earlier.
Seriously?!
Idle Transfiguration.
Tengen's barrier? No, this is...
Remote activation of a cursed technique?!
You have my thanks, Yuji Itadori.
A cursed spirit's mastery of
their technique ceases to progress
from the moment they're absorbed
by Cursed Spirit Manipulation.
Mahito truly matured
through his fight with you.
To be honest, I wanted to have
Jogo, as well, but no matter.
What did you do?
I remotely activated
Idle Transfiguration on
two types of non-sorcerers
that I marked ahead of time.
Tsumiki Fushiguro
One type was people whom I had absorb
cursed objects like Yuji Itadori did,
and the other was people like Junpei
Yoshino who have cursed techniques,
but whose brains were
structured like non-sorcerers.
Now I've adjusted their brains
to match those of sorcerers.
For the former, I gave them
the strength to be vessels,
and the latter have obtained the
ability to activate their techniques.
And now...
I've released the seal
on those cursed objects.
Some of them have been in a deep sleep
after being exposed to my
cursed energy when I marked them,
but they'll soon awaken.
So, starting now,
I'll have them kill each other in order to
deepen their understanding of cursed energy.
I've carefully hand-picked
these people and cursed objects.
Think of it as unleashing a
thousand malevolent Yuji Itadoris.
A thousand?
That's conservative.
You're also underestimating
human rationality.
Do you think people will start
killing each other just because
they were granted power?
There's an order to everything.
I certainly didn't cut corners like
that when making my preparations.
Your questions are starting
to become shallow.
He's pissing me off,
so let's all beat him up together!
I can't move right now, though...
What's the matter, Uraume?
I regenerated my body with
a reverse cursed technique...
This is...
Poison?!
My blood got mixed with
yours through Piercing Blood.
Of course it is.
Wait, we're not getting cover from Mai-chan.
They might still have
more allies over there.
My ally is protecting Aoi,
the girl with the gun, and that suit.
They don't belong here.
Can you move?
Yeah.
I can adjust my body heat.
No problems here.
I'm so done.
We were in the middle of our talk.
The cursed objects that I distributed
are what's left of the sorcerers
I've been secretly making pacts
with for a thousand years.
Of course, I forged my pacts
with more than just sorcerers,
though my pacts with those were
annulled when I obtained this body.
You don't mean...
This is the world of the future.
See you later, Yuji Itadori.
Gojo-sensei!
I have high expectations for you.
Are you listening, Sukuna?
It's starting once again.
The world of Heian,
the golden age of jujutsu!
The following footage was recorded by
our crew, who happened to be on-site
reporting on a different matter at the
time of the incident in Tokyo the other day.
Please have a look.
Uh, it's been about ten minutes
since the blackout, I think?
It's been a while,
and the blackout continues.
Something really crazy is going on.
Sure it's not fake news?
We still cannot contact the station,
so the cause remains unknown,
All the news is covering this, though.
Hmm... Well, I'll be getting home
late today, so have a frozen dinner.
and we have practically
no idea what's going on.
Sure.
All 23 wards are nearly wiped out.
The safety of the Prime Minister's office,
including the Chief Cabinet
Secretary, remains uncertain.
It's a political void!
A literal hole!
No matter how low we estimate it,
we need to make a plan to evacuate
at least five million citizens.
Love hotels, campgrounds, ghost towns...
Use whatever you can, as long as it
has the bare minimum infrastructure.
More importantly, how are we
supposed to explain this to the residents?
There's no point announcing anything
when we don't know the cause!
Also, the government has yet
to make an announcement.
Was this simply the
malfunction of a substation?
Was it terrorism?
Or perhaps... it was a natural
disaster, like an earthquake?
Too many conspiracy theorists
are crawling out.
Either way, the cause remains unclear,
Listen, would you put your phone
away and come help me here?
and we're being forced to wait
while they uncover it.
Very well.
All we can firmly declare
safe are portions of
Okutama, Oume City, Akiruno City, Hachioji City,
Machida City, and various islands.
For now, you mean.
The number of cursed spirits unleashed
is no less than ten million.
You want to enact an evacuation order
on every ward of the entire city?
Afterward, we declare
the wards forbidden to entry.
Make it a real uninhabited zone.
More importantly,
what about our announcement?
Who's making it?
Less "who" and more "how" to make it.
We still can't get a hold
of the deputy secretary?
No, we can't.
I haven't heard anything
from his secretary, either.
What should we do?
Now, now, the upper brass
will figure that out.
For now, we need to establish
contact with each ministry.
The low yen ain't stopping.
That was at least good for exports, right?
The Japanese Business
Federation has lost it?
They won't be doing any
lobbying if everyone's dead.
Move the Prime Minister to Osaka!
At this rate, there'll be a massive
outbreak of cursed spirits everywhere!
Most jujutsu sorcerers are already assigned
to protecting evacuees in the city!
And that outbreak is coming now!
With a power vacuum of this scale,
we may see military intervention
from other nations.
Yes. Huh?
Oh, no.
Yes.
I understand.
They're going to publicly announce
the existence of cursed spirits.
Huh?!
They're going public with cursed spirits?!
Are they seriously suggesting that?!
Apparently, they intend to announce
that cursed spirits only arise in Tokyo.
So the goal is to direct the populace's
leaking cursed energy to Tokyo
and limit the outbreak of
cursed spirits to there, huh?
This is why I recommended Itami as a potential
relocation site after Kansai Airport was built!
Maybe it's better this way?
They wouldn't have reached this decision
if Kasumigaseki was functioning.
Um, once again, we're sharing the latest.
The blackout still continues as before,
and we're unable to contact anyone.
There's been no official announcement, either,
so the cause remains unknown.
The question is, how long will this last—hmm?
LIVE               Unusual Phenomenon in the Capital? Damage Is Spreading
What?  What is that?!
Hey!
Please wait a moment
Huh? What is this?
A movie?
The barrier centered around the Imperial
Palace that was erected in the Meiji era,
and the barrier centered directly
above the Tombs of the Star Corridor,
which was a proposed site for the
relocation of Tokyo in the Bakumatsu era,
will be forcibly expanded out
to the borders of the prefecture.
Come.
It's dangerous here.
I have a warm bath.
I can sing songs, too.
What about my mom?
Your mother, father,
older sister, younger brother,
and teacher are all here.
I don't have a younger brother.
And I hate my teacher.
Are you okay?
Need a drink?
Please?
Sorry.
Did I scare you?
Are you hurt?
Were you with anyone?
Like your mom or dad?
I don't know.
It's all commercial buildings here,
so I guess she's not from around here?
Did you walk a lot?
I see. You worked hard.
You can see them, huh?
That's bad, Rika-chan.
Don't overdo it.
I'm sorry. I hesitated.
I thought I should sit back and watch,
and give him room to work, since the
situation had already progressed so far.
Have you realized yet?
I'm not really on your side.
I'm just a humble beauty who wants to
eradicate cursed spirits from the world.
It might not be much of an apology,
but my allies and I will take responsibility
for delivering the kids who were there.
It's high time I confronted Tengen, too.
What will you do?
Good work, Okkotsu.
You don't really intend to thank me,
so let's just get to the point.
Now you understand that
I'll obey your orders, right?
No amount of killing cursed
spirits will prove anything.
Then forge a pact or whatever you need to.
It doesn't matter that he's
one of Gojo-sensei's students.
He cut off Inumaki-kun's arms in Shibuya.
So I will kill Yuji Itadori.
Notice from Jujutsu Headquarters
1) Suguru Geto's survival was confirmed.
We hereby declare the reinstatement
of his death sentence.
2) Satoru Gojo has been deemed an accomplice in the
Shibuya Incident and is hereby expelled from jujutsu society.
In addition, any attempt to free him from his seal will be deemed a crime.
3) Masamichi Yaga is sentenced to death
for inciting Satoru Gojo and Suguru Geto,
causing the Shibuya Incident.
4) The suspension on Yuji Itadori's
death sentence is hereby revoked, and his
execution shall be carried out promptly.
5) Special-grade sorcerer Yuta Okkotsu
shall be appointed as Yuji Itadori's executioner.
Episode 47
Shibuya Incident - Gate, Close
To Be Continued